Register of the Kyril Drenikoff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1958-1983 (Boxes 44-52)
  - "Bulgarski ordeni i medali," Svoboda, undated (Folder 44: 29)
  - "Bulgarski skitsi ot Tsarigrad," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 44: 30)
  - "Bulgarskoto tsentralno blagotvoritelno obshchestvo i Viktor Iugo,", undated (Folder 44: 31)
  - "Chiprovskata epopeia,", undated (Folder 44: 32)
    Typescript (parts 1-4)
  - "Comportement de la Grèce à l'égard des communautés d'autres nationalités placées sous son autorité,", undated (Folder 44: 33)
  - "Le Congrès du MPO,", undated (Folder 44: 34)
  - "Da si sverim chasovnitsite," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 44: 35)
  - "Défi à la civilisation,", undated (Folder 44: 36)
  - "Deuils pour l'émigration bulgare,", undated (Folder 44: 37)
  - "Dimiter Petkov,", undated (Folder 44: 38)
  - "Diplomat i vladika poboinitsi,", undated (Folder 44: 39)
  - "Do pochitaemia 60-a Kongres na MPO," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 44: 40)
  - "Dobri Chintulov: Po sluchai denia na Narodnite buditeli," Svoboda, undated (Folder 44: 41)
  - "Doktor Konstantin Irechek,", undated (Folder 44: 42)
  - "Doktor Peter Beron," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), undated (Folder 44: 43)
  - "Doktor Stoian Chomakov ,", (1819-1889) undated (Folder 44: 44)
  - "Dosadno nedoglezhdane,", undated (Folder 44: 45)
  - "Du voyage organisé au faux témoignage organisé,", undated (Folder 44: 46)
  - "Dzheims Baucher," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), undated (Folder 44: 47)
  - "L'écroulement des légendes,", undated (Folder 44: 48)
  - "Edin bulgarin vsred otkrivatelie na Amerika,", undated (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - "Edin dostoino izpolnen dolg,", undated (Folder 45: 2)
  - "Edna istina - dva arshina,", undated (Folder 45: 3)
  - "Edna izlozhba v Meksiko," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 45: 4)
  - "Edna malka svetinia," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 45: 5)
  - "Edno kameche se izpliu," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 45: 6)
  - "Evgeni Tiseran,", undated (Folder 45: 7)
  - "Famile royale bulgare,", undated (Folder 45: 8)
    Notes
  - "Frenski vestnik za balkanskata voina,", undated (Folder 45: 9)
  - "Frenskiat kolezh Sv. Kiril i Metodi v Lozenets,", undated (Folder 45: 10)
  - "General Ivan Kolev,", undated (Folder 45: 11)
  - "General Nikola Zhekov,", undated (Folder 45: 12)
  - "Georgi Benkovski,", undated (Folder 45: 13)
  - "Godishnina ot nezavisimosteta na Ukrajna," Makedonska tribuna ('Sobitia' column), undated (Folder 45: 14)
  - "Grigori Tsamblak,", undated (Folder 45: 15)
  - "Iakim Gruev," Svoboda, undated (Folder 45: 16)
  - "Iasi,", undated (Folder 45: 17)
  - "Ilia Marinov - vladyka na Chiprovtsi,", undated (Folder 45: 18)
  - "L'impérialisme russe et la Bulgarie,", undated (Folder 45: 19)
  - "Interesi na Negovo Velichestvo Tsaria,", undated (Folder 45: 20)
  - "Istinata e feniks" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), undated (Folder 45: 21)
  - "Ivan Evstafiev Geshov,", undated (Folder 45: 22)
  - "Iz chuzhdia pechat,", undated (Folder 45: 23)
  - "Iz spomenite na Ben Gurion,", undated (Folder 45: 24)
  - "Izidor Kievski,", undated (Folder 45: 25)
  - "Kak v spaseno znameto na 35-i vrachanski polk," Bulgarski voin, undated (Folder 45: 26)
  - "Khristo Statev i mladezheta,", undated (Folder 45: 27)
  - "Kniaz Aleksander Batemberg," Svoboda, undated (Folder 45: 28)
  - "Kniga koiato ne trebvashe da se napishe" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), undated (Folder 45: 29)
    Review of Blago Dimitrov and Iordan Vasilev. Typescript
  - "Liuben Khristov,", undated (Folder 45: 30)
  - "Liubomir Miletich,", undated (Folder 45: 31)
  - "Lui Lezhe,", undated (Folder 45: 32)
  - "Maistor na chetkata i peroto,", undated (Folder 45: 33)
  - "Malek balkanski pakt,", undated (Folder 45: 34)
  - Message for the Institut des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes, undated (Folder 45: 35)
  - "Mikhail Takev,", undated (Folder 45: 36)
  - "Le mouvement partisan en Bulgarie,", undated (Folder 45: 37)
  - "Mozhe li oshche da se spori," Makedonska tribuna,", undated (Folder 45: 38)
  - "Mustafa Kemal Atatiurk," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), undated (Folder 45: 39)
  - "Na chuzhd grob li plachat,", undated (Folder 45: 40)
  - "Neofit Bozveli khilendarski," Svoboda, undated (Folder 45: 41)
  - "Note de lecture,", undated (Folder 45: 42)
  - Notes on Richard Sorge, undated (Folder 45: 43)
  - "Une nouvelle stratégie d'action et la subversion communiste sur le plan international," Svoboda, undated (Folder 45: 44)
  - "L'oeuvre des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes en Bulgarie,", undated (Folder 45: 45)
  - "Okhridskata arkhiepiskopia,", undated (Folder 45: 46)
  - "Otets Iosif Gagov,", undated (Folder 45: 47)
  - "Otets Ivan Zupan Pochina," broadcast for Radio Vatican, undated (Folder 45: 48)
  - "Otlichen priiatel na Bulgaria,", undated (Folder 45: 49)
  - "Otlichna proiava na nash sonarodnik,", undated (Folder 45: 50)
  - "Pak za komunisticheskia pechat,", undated (Folder 45: 51)
  - "Un pamphlet tendancieux et calomnieux,", undated (Folder 45: 52)
  - "Parizhki spisok na bulgarski arkhiepiskopi,", undated (Folder 45: 53)
  - "Pencho Slaveikov," Svoboda, undated (Folder 45: 54)
  - "Petdesiat godini ot zarobvaneto na Gruzia,", undated (Folder 45: 55)
  - "Peter Delian,", undated (Folder 45: 56)
  - "Pochitane pameteta na profesor Allo Dami," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 45: 57)
  - "Polkovnik Boris Stoianov Drangov," Svoboda, undated (Folder 45: 58)
  - "Pour la Macédoine: Un correspondant de la presse parisienne dans les Balkans en feu ,", 1912-1913 undated (Folder 45: 59)
  - "Pregled na novi knigi,", undated (Folder 45: 60)
  - "Prelisteni stranitsy ot istoriata na bulgarskia narod: Bratia Miladinovy - Angel Konchev - Baba Tonka - Bulgarskoto opolchenie - poleta nad Odrin,", undated (Box-folder 46: 1)
  - "Priem v Parizhe,", undated (Folder 46: 2)
  - "Prinos kem istoriata na borbite za osvobozhdenieto na Makedonia,", undated (Folder 46: 3)
  - "Les problèmes de la lutte anti-communiste en Bulgarie,", undated (Folder 46: 4)
    Typescript. Includes Spanish version
  - "Purvata vozdushna bombardirovka nad Sofia: Spomen na inzh. D. Davidov," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 5)
  - "Putevoditel 'Za nikude'" (under the pseudonym of Is. O. [Iskren Otichkov]), Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 6)
  - "La question macédonienne,", undated (Folder 46: 7)
  - "Raiko Il. Bleskov," Svoboda, undated (Folder 46: 8)
  - "Razkhodka iz edin panair," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 9)
  - "VII Redoven Congres na Bulgarskata Liga za Pravata na Choveka,", undated (Folder 46: 10)
  - "René Sharon,", undated (Folder 46: 11)
  - "La répression communiste en Bulgarie,", undated (Folder 46: 12)
  - "Les réserves bulgares aux conventions de Genève,", undated (Folder 46: 13)
  - Review of an unidentified book on Bulgaria, undated (Folder 46: 14)
  - Review of Zhivko Oshazkov, "Metodologicheskie problemi na edna anketa verkhu religioznosteta v Bulgaria,", undated (Folder 46: 15)
  - "La revue Latch,", undated (Folder 46: 16)
  - "Rimo-katolicheskata tserkva i makedonskite bulgari,", undated (Folder 46: 17)
    Typescript. Includes French version
  - "S novi sili,", undated (Folder 46: 18)
  - "S.A.R. le Prince Kyril de Preslav,", undated (Folder 46: 19)
  - "Sava Bobchev pochina,", undated (Folder 46: 20)
  - "Skrobni vesti,", undated (Folder 46: 21)
  - "Sluchaiat Borislav Ivanchev,", undated (Folder 46: 22)
  - "Sme li izpraveni pred novo robstvo?", undated (Folder 46: 23)
  - Speech about Bulgaria in the name of the Emigration Nationale Bulgare, undated (Folder 46: 24)
  - Speech about Bulgarian anticommunist organizations and Korea, Seoul, Korea, undated (Folder 46: 25)
  - Speech honoring Boris III, Czar of Bulgaria, undated (Folder 46: 26)
  - Speech outlining the activities of various Bulgarian anticommunist organizations, undated (Folder 46: 27)
  - "Staline: A-t-il ordonné la mort du roi Boris III de Bulgarie?", undated (Folder 46: 28)
    Typescript. Includes English version "Did Stalin Order King Boris III's Death?"
  - Statement saluting the participants of the annual conferences organized by the European Council of Freedom and the Anti-Bolshevik Block of Nations (ABN), undated (Folder 46: 29)
  - Statement upon the anniversary of the death of Ianuarius Makgahan, undated (Folder 46: 30)
  - "Stilian Chilingirov," Svoboda, undated (Folder 46: 31)
  - "Stogodishnina,", undated (Folder 46: 32)
  - "Stogodishninata ot smerta na bratia Miladinovi,", undated (Folder 46: 33)
  - "Temni oblatsi nad Balkanskiat poluostrov,", undated (Folder 46: 34)
  - "Titovtsi bez maska,", undated (Folder 46: 35)
  - "Todor Aleksandrov,", undated (Folder 46: 36)
  - "Tridnevni ukrainski torzhestva v Rime,", undated (Folder 46: 37)
  - "Turski danni za naselenieto na Balkanskia poluostrov,", undated (Folder 46: 38)
  - "Use of Terror in Soviet Russia's Foreign Policy: The Bulgarian Case,", undated (Folder 46: 39)
    Typescript. Includes French version "L'usage de la terreur dans la politique étrangère russe et soviétique: Le cas bulgare"
  - "V vrezka s sobitiata v Kosovo" (under the pseudonym of Is. O. [Iskren Otichkov]), undated (Folder 46: 40)
  - "Vasil Petleshkov,", undated (Folder 46: 41)
  - "Vazhno otkritie v sinaiskata pustinia," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 42)
  - "Vestnik Bulgaria,", undated (Folder 46: 43)
    Radio broadcast. Typescript
  - "Victor Hugo et la Société Bulgare de Bienfaisance: Victor Hugo en faveur du peuple bulgare,", undated (Folder 46: 44)
  - "Le volcan balkanique,", undated (Folder 46: 45)
  - "Volket i ovtsete," Svoboda, undated (Folder 46: 46)
  - "Vopros na shans: Razmishlenia na profesor Aldo Dami verkhu nespravedlivostite v istoriata," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 47)
  - "Vozkhvala na Ilinden," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 48)
  - "Za Bulgarskiat tsar Samuil," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 49)
  - "Za etikata na komunisticheskite zhurnalisti,", undated (Folder 46: 50)
  - "Za gzhdulkata na tsar Danil," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 51)
  - "Za imeto na peka Vardar,", undated (Folder 46: 52)
  - "Za obezbulgarenite Bulgari,", undated (Folder 46: 53)
  - "Zaritali se maino de dva akademika," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 54)
  - "Zashcho molchite litsemeri?" Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 46: 55)
  - Speech commemorating Captive Nations Week and the 80th anniversary of the Ilinden insurrection, 1956 (Folder 46: 56)
  - "La Bulgarie dans les relations internationales entre les deux guerres mondiales,", 1959 (Box-folder 47: 1-2)
    Doctoral thesis, La Sorbonne, Paris. Typescript
  - "La Dobroudja,", 1960 (Folder 47: 3)
    Thesis, Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales, Paris. Typescript
  - Essay (by Kyril Drenikoff?) on international organizations, 1961 February 28 (Folder 47: 4)
    Typescript. Includes notes on the European Community by unknown author, 1969
  - "Edna izkliuchitelna kniga,", 1962? (Folder 47: 5)
    Review of Arved Viirlaid, Tombeaux sans croix. Typescript
  - "Vasil Evstativ Aprilov," Svoboda, 1962 (Folder 47: 6)
  - "Novo svidetelstvuvanie,", 1963 (Folder 47: 7)
    Review of Volodymyr Kosyk, L'Ukraine sous le joug colonial russe, 1963. Typescript
  - "Rapports entre OACI et les organisations aéronautiques européennes,", 1963 (Box-folder 48: 1)
    Thesis, Hague Academy of International Law. Research material and typescript
  - "Aleko Konstantinov," Svoboda, 1963 November (Folder 48: 2)
  - "Vasil Levski," Svoboda, 1963 December (Folder 48: 3)
  - "Torzhestvata v Madrid ot 14 do 17 iuni 1965 godina po sluchai X (10) godishninata ot polnoletieto na h.v. tsar Simeon II," (Folder 48: 4)
  - Review of Bernard Moinet, L'opium rouge, 1966 (Folder 48: 5)
  - Review of Henri de Montfort, Le massacre de Katyn: Crime russe ou crime allemand?, 1966 (Folder 48: 6)
  - Review of Roger Delpay, Les loups vont par deux, 1966 (Folder 48: 7)
  - Review of Teodoro Palacios, 12 ans en enfer: Capitaine Palacios, 1966 (Folder 48: 8)
  - Review of Tibor Méray, La rupture Moscou-Pékin, 1966 (Folder 48: 9)
  - Review of L'attività della Santa Sede nel 1967 (Folder 48: 10)
  - Review of Liubomir Vankov, "Frenski elementi v Bulgarslia iazik," and Marin Pundev, "Korenite na bulgrskia natsionalism,", 1967? (Folder 48: 11)
  - "Georgi Papazov,", 1967 (Folder 48: 12)
  - Review of Joseph Girard-Reydet, Le père Gervais Quenard, supérieur général des Assomptionistes, 1967 (Folder 48: 13)
  - "Lettere dall'oriente, Angelo G. Roncalli,", 1968? (Folder 48: 14)
    Review of Angelo G. Roncalli, Lettere dall'oriente e altre inedite. Typescript
  - Review of L'attività della Santa Sede nel 1968 (Folder 48: 15)
  - L'église catholique en Bulgarie, 1968 (Folder 48: 16-18)
    Background material and reviews
  - La mort mystérieuse d'un roi (under the pseudonym of Strachimir Belphegoroff), 1968 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    Typescript and galleys
  - "Episkop Ilia Marinov,", 1969 (Folder 49: 2)
    Broadcast, Radio Vatican, Bulgarian Section. Typescript
  - Review of Christo Statev's brochure on the Bulgarian Communist Party, 1969 (Folder 49: 3)
  - "Stefan Stambolov,", 1969 (Folder 49: 4)
  - "Sur la mort mystérieuse du roi Boris III de Bulgarie: Staline est-il coupable?,", 1969 (Folder 49: 5)
  - "Sovetit v Sredizemno more,", 1970? (Folder 49: 6)
    Review of Les Soviétiques en Méditerranée. Typescript
  - "L'écroulement des légendes," La Mole, 1970 (Folder 49: 7)
  - "Lénine, créateur du système tyrannique et du nouvel empire,", 1970 (Folder 49: 8)
  - "Pour l'unification et l'indépendance des nations divisées,", 1970 (Folder 49: 9)
  - "Vodata na reka mesta otovena," Makedonska tribuna, 1970 (Folder 49: 10)
  - Letter to the editor regarding the death of Boris III, Czar of Bulgaria (date written), 1970 March 12 (Folder 49: 11)
  - "Palestinskata odisea,", 1971? (Folder 49: 12)
    Review of Nedko S. Etinoff, Palestinian odyssey. Typescript
  - Speech relating to Croatian independence, 1971 April 10 (Folder 49: 13)
  - "Orhrid Ekspres," Makedonska tribuna, 1971 May (Folder 49: 14)
  - "Za roliata i za zadachata," Makedonska tribuna (under the pseudonym of Georgi Lazov), 1971 May (Folder 49: 15)
  - "Vaticana i vtorata svetovna voina," Makedonska tribuna, 1971 June (Folder 49: 16)
  - Speech, 50th Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, 1971 October (Folder 49: 17)
  - "Deklaratsiata pred suda na Valentin Moroz,", 1972 January (Folder 49: 18)
  - "Imena i fakti ot istoriata na bulgarskata natsia," Makedonska tribuna, 1972 February (Folder 49: 19)
  - "Evreisko poselenie po bolragskite zemi," Makedonska tribuna, 1972 October (Folder 49: 20)
  - Speech, 51st Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, 1972 October (Folder 49: 21)
  - "Biografia za edin diktator" (under the pseudonym of D. V.), Makedonska tribuna, 1972 December (Folder 49: 22)
  - Review of Ivan Matekalo, Les dessous du terrorisme international, 1973? (Folder 49: 23)
  - "," Svoboda, 28 Avgust 1943 - 28 Avgust 1973 1973 (Folder 49: 24)
  - "Belezhiti bulgari," Svoboda, 1973 (Folder 49: 25)
    Typescript. Includes information on Dobri Chintulov, Georgi Papazov, Grigori Perlichev, and Khristofor Zhefarivitch
  - "Edin unikalen bulgarski rukopis ot XVII vek" (under the pseudonym of C. de V.), Makedonska tribuna, 1973 (Folder 49: 26)
  - "General Danail Nikolaev," Svoboda, 1973 (Folder 49: 27)
  - "Ivan Vazov v Solun," Makedonska tribuna, 1973 (Folder 49: 28)
  - "Kuzman Shapkarev," Makedonska tribuna, 1973 (Folder 49: 29)
  - "Pregled na novi knigi," Svoboda, 1973 (Folder 49: 30)
  - "Razgornati stranitsy ot istoriata na Bulgarskiat Narod: Subota, 26 Iuli 811 godina," Svoboda, 1973 (Folder 49: 31)
  - "Skrobni vesti," Svoboda, 1973 (Folder 49: 32)
  - "Stefan I. Verkovitch," Makedonska tribuna, 1973 (Folder 49: 33)
  - "Stari ungarski svedenia za Makedinia," Makedonska tribuna, 1973 February (Folder 49: 34)
  - "The Balkanic Vulcano,", 1973 July (Folder 49: 35)
  - "Qu'est-ce qui fait trembler Moscou?,", 1973 August (Folder 49: 36)
  - Statement in the name of the Mouvement de Libération Bulgare about the Patriarch of the Bulgarian Orthodox Church, 1973 August 2 (Folder 49: 37)
  - "Kiliinite uchilishcha v Makedinia," Makedonska tribuna, 1973 September (Folder 49: 38)
  - Speech, 52nd Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, 1973 October (Folder 49: 39)
  - "A la conférence pour les minorités nationales,", 1974 (Folder 49: 40)
  - "Journal bulgare pour le synode ukrainien," Shliakh peremogy, 1974 (Folder 49: 41)
  - "Letopisets na borbite i na vozzhedeliata na bratskia khorvatski narod," Makedonska tribuna, 1974 (Folder 49: 42)
  - "Une nouvelle stratégie d'action de la subversion communiste sur le plan international,", 1974 (Folder 49: 43)
  - "Oskar Fingal Yaild i Bulgaria," Makedonska tribuna, 1974 (Folder 49: 44)
  - Review of René Reouven (under the pseudonym of G. L. [Georgi Lazov]), Dictionnaire des assassins, 1974? (Folder 49: 45)
  - "Za pisatelite i za bukvoredachite" (under the pseudonym of G. G.), 1974? (Folder 49: 46)
    Review of Simeon Pravchanov, Put razmirnometezhen: Kn. za sudbata i tvorchestvoto na Khriso T. Asenov. Typescript
  - Speech, 53rd Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, 1974 October (Folder 49: 47)
  - "Zhak Natan povdiga zavesata" (under the pseudonym of G. G.), Makedonska tribuna, 1974 November (Folder 49: 48)
  - Review of Ivan Mikhailov, "Spomeni,", 1974 November 14 (Folder 49: 49)
  - "Un manuscrit bulgare du XVIIe siècle" (under the pseudonym of C. D. de Velboudj), 1975 (Folder 49: 50)
  - "Nema go maistera" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1975 (Folder 49: 51)
  - "Un seul combat, un seul but - la liberté,", 1975 (Folder 49: 52)
  - "Dve godishnini," Makedonska tribuna, 1975 January (Folder 49: 53)
  - "Poseshchenie na edin muzei," Makedonska tribuna, 1975 March (Folder 49: 54)
  - "Da ne zabravim Tarlis," Makedonska tribuna, 1975 July (Folder 49: 55)
  - "Ne e lud koi iziada dva zelnika" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1975 November (Folder 49: 56)
  - "Nov prevod na romana 'Pod igoto',", 1976? (Folder 49: 57)
    Review of Ivan Minchov Vazov, Pod igoto. Typescript
  - "Ilarion Makariopolski," Svoboda, 1976 (Folder 49: 58)
  - "Nov vazhen trud na profesor Aldo Dami,", 1976 (Folder 49: 59)
    Review of Aldo Dami, Les frontières européennes de 1900 à 1975 Histoire territoriale de l'Europe. Typescript
  - "Razkhodka iz Tsarigrad," Makedonska tribuna, 1976 January (Folder 50: 1)
  - "Ako mine" (under the pseudonym of Dimiter Iskrenov), Makedonska tribuna, 1976 March (Folder 50: 2)
  - "Istoricheski rechnik za svetite," Makedonska tribuna, 1976 March (Folder 50: 3)
  - "Boloto ne e cherno,", 1976 May (Folder 50: 4)
  - "Komunisticheskata represia v Pirinska Makedonia," Makedonska tribuna, 1976 May (Folder 50: 5)
  - "Spomen za edin dostoen bulgarin" (under the pseudonym of K. G. D.), 1976 July (Folder 50: 6)
  - "Zhivot za partiata" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1976 July (Folder 50: 7)
  - "Bulgarski narodni pesni: Sobrani ot Bratia Miladinovi," Makedonska tribuna, 1976 October (Folder 50: 8)
  - Speech, 55th Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, 1976 October 7 (Folder 50: 9)
  - "Les Balkans, point chaud de la crise mondiale," speech, Anti-Bolshevik Block of Nations conference, Manchester, Great Britain, 1976 October 15-18 (Folder 50: 10)
  - "Biva, biva ama chak tolkoz" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1976 October 28 (Folder 50: 11)
  - "Raiko Zhinzifov," Makedonska tribuna, 1976 December (Folder 50: 12)
  - "Khrand Samuelian," Le Monde, 1977 (Folder 50: 13)
  - "La radio propagande communiste,", 1977 (Folder 50: 14)
    Notes, typescript, and printed copy. Includes English and Spanish versions
  - "Kavaleri na smerteta" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1977 January 20 (Folder 50: 15)
  - "Legenda za edin rodootstupnik," Makedonska tribuna, 1977 January 20 (Folder 50: 16)
  - "Balkanski paraleli" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1977 January 28 (Folder 50: 17)
  - "Edna belezhita bulgarka," Makedonska tribuna, 1977 February (Folder 50: 18)
  - "Pak za devetoiunskia prevrat v 1923 godina" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1977 March 31 (Folder 50: 19)
  - Speech, 56th Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, Toronto, Canada, 1977 October (Folder 50: 20)
  - "Novo izdanie na vazhna kniga,", 1978? (Folder 50: 21)
    Review of Ivan Mikhailov, V.M.R.O. Typescript
  - "Po povod na edna stogodishnina," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 February (Folder 50: 22)
  - "Sluchaina rabota," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 March (Folder 50: 23)
  - "Na edno izlozhenie," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 May (Folder 50: 24)
  - "Za bulgarskia Tsar Samuil," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 May (Folder 50: 25)
  - "15 avgust 778 godina," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 August (Folder 50: 26)
  - "Bulgarski chitalishcha v Makedonia do Berlinskiat Kongres 1978 godina," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 August (Folder 50: 27)
  - Speech, 57th Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, Toronto, Canada, 1978 October 5 (Folder 50: 28)
  - "Falshifikatsii novi i stari," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 December (Folder 50: 29)
  - "Kem proizkhoda na makedonskit bulgari," Makedonska tribuna, 1978 December (Folder 50: 30)
  - "Bulgarskiat komunisticheski pechat i istinata," Svoboda, 1979(?) (Folder 50: 31)
  - "Novo klubno pomeshchenie na druzhestvo 'Todor Aleksandrov' v Belgia," Makedonska tribuna, 1979 (Folder 50: 32)
  - Speech, Bulgarian League on Human Rights, Brussels, Belgium, 1979 (Folder 50: 33)
  - "Stershel izbegva da zhili" (under the pseudonym of Gravets), Makedonska tribuna, 1979 (Folder 50: 34)
  - "Za etikata na komunisticheskite zhurnalisti," Svoboden narod, 1979 (Folder 50: 35)
  - "Liubopiten fakt,", 1979 February (Folder 50: 36)
  - "Zmia v pazvata" (under the pseudonym of Goge Lazov), Pogled, 1979 February (Folder 50: 37)
  - "Ima samo Serbia" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1979 May (Folder 50: 38)
  - "Senzatsionno razkritie po atentata v Marsilia" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1979 May (Folder 50: 39)
  - "Starobulgarski nadpisi v Egeiska Makedonia," Makedonska tribuna, 1979 May (Folder 50: 40)
  - Speech, 58th Congress of the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada, 1979 October (Folder 50: 41)
  - "Apologia na predatelstvoto" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1979 November (Folder 50: 42)
  - "Da ne izvertvame istinata" (under the pseudonym of G. L. [Georgi Lazov]), Makedonska tribuna, 1980 (Folder 50: 43)
  - "Khristo Uzunov," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), 1980 (Folder 50: 44)
  - "Parteni Zografski," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), 1980 (Folder 50: 45)
  - "Feliks Kanits," Makedonska tribuna, 1980 February (Folder 50: 46)
  - "Petishcha izverveni" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1980 February (Folder 50: 47)
  - "Iz novata entsiklopedia 'Bulgaria'" (under the pseudonym of G. L. [Georgi Lazov]), Makedonska tribuna, 1980 May (Folder 50: 48)
  - "Izlozhba na dervorezbarsko izkustvo,", 1980 May (Folder 50: 49)
  - "Pred televizioniat ekran,", 1980 May (Folder 50: 50)
  - "Za Kiututsite" (under the pseudonym of G. Lazov), Makedonska tribuna, 1980 May (Folder 50: 51)
  - "Zagrizhenost za polozhenieto na Balkanite,", 1980 May (Folder 50: 52)
  - Speech, Bulgarian League of Human Rights in Exile, 1980 October 3 (Folder 50: 53)
  - "Contribution à l'étude de l'héraldique bulgare,", 1981 (Folder 50: 54)